<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>clt on Lithouse</title>
    <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/tags/clt/</link>
    <description>Recent content in clt on Lithouse</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.lithouse.eu/tags/clt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>CLT inside doors</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200409_clt__inside_door_in_almere/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200409_clt__inside_door_in_almere/</guid>
      <description>Another photo from a CLT interior. Look what you can do with CLT: inside doors without frames, and without hinges! The handle is all you see.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLT in Almere</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200408_clt_in_almere/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200408_clt_in_almere/</guid>
      <description>We have been busy lately with preparing new projects and we had little time to place posts on our website. But now while cleaning a laptop we found some photos that we better place on our website right away and then later we will go search for the rest of the photos, because for sure we had some better ones.
  This project we finished about six months ago. The photo above was taken about three weeks before hand-over of the house.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Josephine, minimalist to the max</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/projects/20200404_josephine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/projects/20200404_josephine/</guid>
      <description>The Josephine is a combination of panel and cross laminated timber, or CLT. The walls are traditional panel walls that you will see everywhere nowadays, while the overlay structure is made from CLT, 10 cm massive wood. The inside walls are finished with multiplex which creates an industrial interior.
  The glass facade is what it it all about. This house is located on the edge of a small village, overlooking farmland the the South-West.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>