<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lithouse</title>
    <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Lithouse</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.lithouse.eu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>We are Lithouse</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/start/01_we_are_lithouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/start/01_we_are_lithouse/</guid>
      <description>We are Lithouse. We build top quality wooden houses. Beautiful wooden houses, made to last for ages, made to measure, made for comfort.
  We specialise in solid, durable, energy-efficient houses. We try to use natural and ecological materials where we can. And we pride ourselves in making beautiful houses, not just run-of-the-mill standard living boxes but beautiful designs that make you feel happy every time you come home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Only top-quality</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/start/10_only_top_quality/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/start/10_only_top_quality/</guid>
      <description>We only build top-quality. No quick fixes, no rush jobs, only solutions that will last. We prefer simple reliable technologies and stable solutions. We take our time to design, and we take our time to produce and assemble. We prefer things that are stable and don&amp;rsquo;t break.
  We want to build for ourselves, and for the next generations. It is not difficult, it&amp;rsquo;s just a matter of caring more about build-quality than about market share, because we think that comes automatically if you keep your eye on quality and customer satisfaction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Craftmanship and Experience</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/start/20_craftmanship_and_experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/start/20_craftmanship_and_experience/</guid>
      <description>Craftmanship is difficult to measure. It is a combination of training and experience, and of interest and willingness to perform and to make things better.
  It is about pride about your own job, about understanding that what you do is special and that you are able to deliver quality. We surely feel like that about our products and about the ways we work.
  We have no company slogans, we are just carpenters with a drive to build something nice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We build made-to-measure</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/start/60_we_build_made_to_measure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/start/60_we_build_made_to_measure/</guid>
      <description>We build made-to-measure. No standard catalogue, only designs to your requirements. Takes a little extra effort, pays out for a lifetime.
  As far as cost is concerned there is not much difference because we have small factories and no big production lines that need to churn out massive numbers of houses. There is a little extra cost for the design stage, but it is minimal when compared to your total project cost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We build all over Europe</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/start/80_we_build_all_over_europe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/start/80_we_build_all_over_europe/</guid>
      <description>We can build everywhere in Europe, but mainly in France and The Netherlands. We produce in Lithuania, our installation teams travel to your building site.
  Depending on the size of your project we show up with tree to six men teams, and we will take somewhere between five and twelve weeks to fully build your house. A log house normally takes slightly more time, but only slightly.
  Our main markets at the moment are France and The Netherlands, but we also build in Portugal, Belgium and Denmark.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Electricity box</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20210619_meterkast/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20210619_meterkast/</guid>
      <description>We were doing a hand-over inspection of a house that we had finished, and then we saw the electricity box. Very often these boxes are a little ehh&amp;hellip; unorganized, to put it kindly. Apparantly the idea is: you close the door, you don&amp;rsquo;t see it, why bother.
But this one was different. Done by an electrician with a little OCD. Very nice!
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yellow and blue log house</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20210215_yellow-and_blue_log_house/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20210215_yellow-and_blue_log_house/</guid>
      <description>With temperatures going down in Lithuania, and wind coming from the North-East, usually after a few days the Dutch go skating. And indeed, with Lithuanian temperatures going down to -25 Celcius, the ice started growing in The Netherlands and then the Dutch get into this frenzy where they all hope for the Great Event: the Elfstedentocht.
  And with Covid-19 the Dutch government did not want to let that happen, twenty thousand people on the ice was not a good idea, but also, they were reluctant to call off an event for which the Dutch had been waiting more than twenty years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chamonix chalet, a modern and exclusive design that stands out</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/projects/20210203_chamonix_chalet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/projects/20210203_chamonix_chalet/</guid>
      <description>Next to the Mont Blanc A beautiful three bedroom chalet built in the valley of Mont Blanc mountain, in Les Houches, with a big vide. Splendid view towards the Mont Blanc.
  While building this house we tried to keep traditional local style yet we have implemented some modern details. A contemporary look, with Siberian larch cladding on the exterior and a plasterboard finish on the interior.
  Vide One of the nicest features of this house is a vide which allows to enjoy beautiful views of the Mont Blanc mountain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>American barn</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20210126_american_barn/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20210126_american_barn/</guid>
      <description>Almost finished: an American barn. More to follow&amp;hellip; In Almere in The Netherlands by the way, where something comparable, but bigger, has been built a couple of years ago: the &amp;ldquo;Rode Donders&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chalet Fifi in St. Jean d&#39;Aulps</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20210125_st_jean_d_aulps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20210125_st_jean_d_aulps/</guid>
      <description>Last year we built a panel house in St. Jeans d&amp;rsquo;Aulps, about ten minutes from Morzine in France. And we promised to add some more photo. Here they are.
  It looks like a log house, but like many houses in the Alps it actually is a panel house. We also have photos from the interior and then the difference is more obvious. We will show you later.
  The style is very different from our Eric &amp;amp; Flo or the At &amp;amp; Alet, but this house totally fits in it&amp;rsquo;s environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New loghouse in Oosterwold</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20210122_loghuis_in_oosterwold/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20210122_loghuis_in_oosterwold/</guid>
      <description>Just handed over to client: a new loghouse in Oosterwold, Netherlands. Inspired by the Eric &amp;amp; Flo, 120 m2 brutto surface.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cold</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20210115_cold/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20210115_cold/</guid>
      <description>It is well known that timber from the North is heavier. It grows slower, and it is more dense. Better quality wood.
We came back from a business meeting just South of Vilnius and when we drove through a forest, we made this short movie. Nice, made us think of slow growing pine.
  And then in the evening when we came back from work, we looked at the dashboard and saw the temperature&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Larch getting grey</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20210112_larch_getting_grey/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20210112_larch_getting_grey/</guid>
      <description>We often use larch on the facades of our houses, because it is very weather resistant. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t rot, needs no maintenance, protects your house for fifty years.
But there is one thing about larch that is not to everybodies liking: it turns grey. Some people like the natural greying of larch, because it is natural. But others prefer to keep the original colours, for instance as in this house.
  We like the greying, but if you want to keep the original yellowish-orange tint of larch, then you must treat the facade with special products.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eric &amp; Flo</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20210111_eric_and_flo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20210111_eric_and_flo/</guid>
      <description>The Eric &amp;amp; Flo still is, after eight years, the house for which we receive most requests.
  These photos we received today from our clients in the Lozère. Winter wonderland with a beautiful house&amp;hellip;
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wooden logs and cracks</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20201229_wooden_logs_and_cracks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20201229_wooden_logs_and_cracks/</guid>
      <description>Log houses and cracks Log houses are built from wooden logs, that is: solid or laminated wooden beams, from eight centimeters thick upto thirty centimeters thick. We usually build our walls twelve or sixteen centimeters thick. Twelve is more than enough for a two-level house, but if you got money to spare then sixteen centimeters just looks nice. Otherwise there is little difference.
  But what about cracks? Yes, especially solid wooden logs do crack, and quite a bit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>St. Jean d&#39;Aulps</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20201213_st_jean_d_alps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20201213_st_jean_d_alps/</guid>
      <description>When we rebuild our website we lost quite some content. A post about a house that we built last year in St. Jean d&amp;rsquo;Aulps (just 10 minutes North of Morzine) also disappeared in cyberspace, so now we place it again.
  Although it looks like a log house, this actually is a panel house. We built the wooden part, a local contractor did the concrete foundation (but we supplied the windows that went into the concrete part).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unloading in the rain, again</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20201123_unloading_in_the_rain_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20201123_unloading_in_the_rain_2/</guid>
      <description>And another photo of unloading, and this time the rain had just stopped. Our client watched while we were busy with panels and trucks and a crane, and she took a photo.
Look at the reflection. You don&amp;rsquo;t need a fancy camera to see the beauty of reflections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unloading in the rain</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20201006_unloading_in_the_rain/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20201006_unloading_in_the_rain/</guid>
      <description>Right after we wrote something about building sites and mud, we start with another project in the polder. And guess what&amp;hellip; rain with the first truck.
  At least we got some nice photos, taken by our client. Our men were less enthousiastic. Minus twenty degrees Celcius is ok for them, but water&amp;hellip;
  At least next week will be better.
    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stuck in the mud</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200925_more_mud/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200925_more_mud/</guid>
      <description>Not all building sites are easily accessible. Some are in the mountains and the trucks have to make tight U-turns as they climb the mountain, other building sites have no roads at all and we have to unload somewhere else and bring our building materials with some flatbed car behind a tractor.
  And then there are building sites that have something that looks like a road, only it isn&amp;rsquo;t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travels and restaurants</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200924_travelling_and_restaurants/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200924_travelling_and_restaurants/</guid>
      <description>Since our factories are in Lithuania, and our clients mostly in France and The Netherlands, we travel a lot. And we jump from one culture to the other, and we never notice. Except, every now and then, we feel a difference, like yesterday. We had had a meeting in the Nort-East of Lithuania, five kilometers from Belorussia. Russia itself starts fifty kilometers further and from there it is Russia all the way until Vladivostok, next to North-Korea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walls and rafters ready</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200907_walls_ready/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200907_walls_ready/</guid>
      <description>We started with this project end of August, and now we are two weeks down the road: walls ready, rafter are on the roof.
  Our engineers decided that they needed a really serious beam at the top of the roof, serious as in: more than 300 kilo, not something that you just lift and place on top. Here comes a crane again&amp;hellip;
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mud</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200831_mud/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200831_mud/</guid>
      <description>Building houses is nice, but mud is not. And when we build, there is always mud.
Even worse is building in the rain. If it rains we go sit inside. But then you want a cup of coffee. So you have to go outside again, to get water, through the mud in the rain&amp;hellip;
  Naja, tomorrow will be better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gardening while building</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200830_gardening_while_building/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200830_gardening_while_building/</guid>
      <description>Building a new house takes ages. Years, literally. Buying a plot, making a design, asking for permissions, changing the design, waiting, changing a bit more, waiting a little longer. And all the time you are mentally busy, but physically you can do nothing, except wait. Just wait.
  But some clients can&amp;rsquo;t wait. They start with the garden. Grass, trees, hedges. And why not&amp;hellip; We can tell you why not: because in a minute we will show up with our fifteen ton crane and turn your garden into a wasteland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stucco on the outside</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200829_stucco_on_the_outside/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200829_stucco_on_the_outside/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes it looks as if we only use larch on the outisde of our houses. But that is not correct, we can use other materials as well. We can offer painted pine, and also we can do stucco.
  In the case of stucco: first we finish the outside with Knauf Aquapenel or Steico Protect, then later we add the stucco layer on top. These images are from a house that we handed over in July 2020, with only the Knauf Aquapanel, as this client will add the stucco layer hoimself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cake and champagne</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200829_married/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200829_married/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes we&amp;rsquo;re lucky.
Yesterday we started with the build of a new loghouse near Rotterdam. Step one: unloading of the truck. The future owners of the house had arranged a crane for us. Usually we have to work with a one-tonne crane or a small Manitou, but this time we saw a 40-tonne crane driving onto the dike. Or 90 tonne, we don&amp;rsquo;t know but it was big. A few hoists, and our truck was empty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>House ready</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200829_house_ready/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200829_house_ready/</guid>
      <description>In the South of The Netherlands we built a panel house. Some clients don&amp;rsquo;t like wood on ths inside, and in that case a panel house is the perfect solution as you can finish the walls any way you like. This client chose larch on the outside, vertical as per architect design and in combination with a Ruukki sheet metal roof, and stucco on the inside.
  We are almost ready.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second item in Google</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200824_second_item_in_google/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200824_second_item_in_google/</guid>
      <description>We searched using Google for &amp;ldquo;images of modern log houses&amp;rdquo;, because obviously we are curious what our colleagues are doing. And guess what: the second item that Google presented to us was our own house, the Eric &amp;amp; Flo. We take it as a compliment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How quickly can we build</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200730_how_to_build_quickly/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200730_how_to_build_quickly/</guid>
      <description>Construction speed is an important factor for consumers. Which we honestly find a little odd, because a full new build projects takes a year at least, usually two years and sometimes up to three years. Making designs, doing calculations, getting permits, sometimes it seems to take ages, and so we do not always understand why we should do the actual construction in just a few weeks when the entire project takes two years anyways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New project</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200608_start_of_new_project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200608_start_of_new_project/</guid>
      <description>Today we started with a new project in The Netherlands. We are going to build a panel house, about 180 m2. The foundation is ready, crane is waiting, assembly crew arrived during the weekend, and Monday morning ten &amp;lsquo;o clock first truck arrived. We will need five trucks for this project.
  There is very little space around the house, the truck can not get there. So we unload one kilometer down the road and place all materials in two containers, which we then drive to the building site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foundations for a wooden house</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200417_foundations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200417_foundations/</guid>
      <description>What are the requirements for a foundation for a wooden house? They are nothing specials, i.e., not very different from the requirements for a traditional brick &amp;amp; mortar house foundation. A wooden house is lighter, but we don&amp;rsquo;t think that makes a lot of difference for the foundation itself. For us, as wooden house builders, there are three requirements: the foundation should be flat, it should let us anchor the house firmly, and the pipes and guides for water and electricity should be at the exact right spot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Russian wooden houses</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200409_old_russian_wooden_houses/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200409_old_russian_wooden_houses/</guid>
      <description>In East Europe wooden houses are everywhere. In the smaller villages almost every houses is a wooden house. Until recently these house were a little different from the house that we build:
 round logs, not laminated no additional insulation a little air leak here and there is ok lots of beautiful decorations painted.    And then finally: often without a serious foundation. Especially in Siberia houses are built with a minimal foundation on top of the permafrost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLT inside doors</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200409_clt__inside_door_in_almere/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200409_clt__inside_door_in_almere/</guid>
      <description>Another photo from a CLT interior. Look what you can do with CLT: inside doors without frames, and without hinges! The handle is all you see.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLT in Almere</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200408_clt_in_almere/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200408_clt_in_almere/</guid>
      <description>We have been busy lately with preparing new projects and we had little time to place posts on our website. But now while cleaning a laptop we found some photos that we better place on our website right away and then later we will go search for the rest of the photos, because for sure we had some better ones.
  This project we finished about six months ago. The photo above was taken about three weeks before hand-over of the house.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life expectancy of a wooden house</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200405_life_expectancy_of_a_log_house/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200405_life_expectancy_of_a_log_house/</guid>
      <description>Contrary to popular belief, wooden houses have a very high life expectancy. Of course wood should be protected from humidity, but if the owner takes care of his house it will last very long. When designing a wooden house we make sure that water can always escape from the house and that walls are ventilated. What would then be life expectancy of a wooden house?
We have several examples of old wooden houses in Europe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building in our Europe</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200404_building_in_europe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200404_building_in_europe/</guid>
      <description>Since our building sites are all over Europe, we travel a lot. And we meet people from all over Europe. English clients, French plumbers, Italian architects, Polish truck drivers and Russian émigrés in Spain. We love it that our generation was able to build this continent where we can travel freely in all directions.
 Here we are waiting for a Manitou to unload a truck in France. People on these photos communicate in French, Lithuanian, Russian, Polish and English, all at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eric &amp; Flo, beauty at 1250 meter height</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/projects/20200402_eric_and_flo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/projects/20200402_eric_and_flo/</guid>
      <description>The Eric &amp;amp; Flo is one of our showroom models. We built this house in 2012 in The Lozère at a height of 1250 meters. In winter it gets seriously cold here, temperatures of -15 degrees Celcius are the norm. Last time we visited this client was in February 2019 en then they had half a meter of snow.
  The simplicity of the design is striking. A simple tilted roof and a wooden planks bardage on the outside with modern corners, and no stick-through miters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Josephine, minimalist to the max</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/projects/20200404_josephine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/projects/20200404_josephine/</guid>
      <description>The Josephine is a combination of panel and cross laminated timber, or CLT. The walls are traditional panel walls that you will see everywhere nowadays, while the overlay structure is made from CLT, 10 cm massive wood. The inside walls are finished with multiplex which creates an industrial interior.
  The glass facade is what it it all about. This house is located on the edge of a small village, overlooking farmland the the South-West.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three types of walls</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200401_three_types_of_walls/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200401_three_types_of_walls/</guid>
      <description>Lithouse build houses with three types of walls:
 panel walls log walls cross laminated timber walls  They all have pro&amp;rsquo;s and con&amp;rsquo;s, let&amp;rsquo;s dive into the details.
Panel walls Panel walls are essentially hollow boxes filled with insulation material. You build a frame from 195 x 60 mm beams, and front and back you close with an 18 mm OSB-plate. Now you have a hollow box, say 2 x 3 meters and 231 mm thick.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turn-key construction</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200328_turn_key/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200328_turn_key/</guid>
      <description>Contractors come in sizes and shapes. Big ones, small ones, contractors that build wooden houses, or masonry houses, contrators that do individual homes and contractors that build appartment blocks. Not every contractor is suitable for your project. An important aspect in your selection process is turn-key.
What is turn-key? There are different definitions of turn-key. Ours is that we:
include:
 foundation roof and walls, outside fully finished, inside without stucco doors and windows, double or triple glass electrical installation, solar panels floor heating, heat pump, boiler waste water, fresh water, tapwater, and  excluding:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Beautiful Design</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200326_goed_gelukt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200326_goed_gelukt/</guid>
      <description>We are builders and we are proud of our houses because of the techniques and materials that we use. Our houses are robust, sturdy, they have very high insulation values and the are build to withstand ages. But all that means nothing when it comes to aesthetics.
  A nice design is just that, nice, and that is why we often cooperate with the architects from OxL. Because no matter how nice our designs are, these OxL boys always manage to make it nicer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A beautiful design, the At &amp; Alet</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/projects/20200326_beautiful_design/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/projects/20200326_beautiful_design/</guid>
      <description>We are builders and we are proud of our houses because of the techniques and materials that we use. Our houses are robust, sturdy, they have very high insulation values and they are build to withstand ages. But all that means nothing when it comes to aesthetics.
A nice design is just that, nice, and that is why we often cooperate with the architects from OxL. Because no matter how nice our designs are, these OxL guys always manage to make it nicer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amber house, overlooking the hills from your terrace</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/projects/20200406_tombeboeuf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/projects/20200406_tombeboeuf/</guid>
      <description>This house we built in 2016 in Tombeboeuf, right between Bordeaux and Toulouse. Again a traditional loghouse with a larch facade, or &amp;ldquo;bardage en melèze&amp;rdquo; as they say in France. Massive beams supporting the roof.
  Our marketing manager Vaida on the terrace. She felt pity to leave the house as she liked both the house and the environment, but duty calls, we have to work on the next house&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lucky shot</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200331_lucky_shot/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200331_lucky_shot/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes a picture is unexpectedly nice. We were inspecting a house and took a picture of the roof. In the top you can see 5 centimeters roof overhanging the wall, we must fix that.
When we later looked at the photo we liked it because of the contrails. Not very eco but nice nonetheless.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New website</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200220_we_build_a_new_website/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200220_we_build_a_new_website/</guid>
      <description>As our old website was too complex and difficult to maintain, we kicked it out. We prefer simple stuff. So we are now in the process of rebuilding our website, but as you can see it is all still quite half-baked. We decided to put it on the web anyways, at least you can see our contact details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Timelapse assembly of a loghuis</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200327_assembling_a_log_house/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200327_assembling_a_log_house/</guid>
      <description>In 2017 we built a loghouse on an island in The Netherlands. Quite an operation: getting a permit to drive a 24-ton truck onto the dike, then unloading to a barge, and then unloading on the island. After returning from a project in the Alps this was a little different for our assembly crew, going to work every day with tug boat.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Timelapse assembly of a loghuis</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/timelapse/20200327_assembling_a_log_house/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/timelapse/20200327_assembling_a_log_house/</guid>
      <description>In 2017 we built a loghouse on an island in The Netherlands. Quite an operation: getting a permit to drive a 24-ton truck onto the dike, then unloading to a barge, and then unloading on the island. After returning from a project in the Alps this was a little different for our assembly crew, going to work every day with tug boat.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>404</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200406_404/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200406_404/</guid>
      <description>Oops, you asked for a page that doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist on our new website. Bummer. We will rebuild that page later, for now please have a look around on our new website&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/contact/</guid>
      <description>Office Netherlands:
Vredelaan 18
1318 AS Almere
Netherlands
Office Lithuania:
Kauno g. 11-4
Ukmerge
Lithuania
tel. +370 688 29898
Phone Numbers:
Ysbrand Galama: +31 6 534 65265
Vaida Vaitkunaite: +370 688 29898
Company Registrations:
Chamber of Commerce, KvK: NL-32162173
VAT/TVA-no: NL-821523405B01</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>