<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>design on Lithouse</title>
    <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/tags/design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in design on Lithouse</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.lithouse.eu/tags/design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Chamonix chalet, a modern and exclusive design that stands out</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/projects/20210203_chamonix_chalet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/projects/20210203_chamonix_chalet/</guid>
      <description>Next to the Mont Blanc A beautiful three bedroom chalet built in the valley of Mont Blanc mountain, in Les Houches, with a big vide. Splendid view towards the Mont Blanc.
  While building this house we tried to keep traditional local style yet we have implemented some modern details. A contemporary look, with Siberian larch cladding on the exterior and a plasterboard finish on the interior.
  Vide One of the nicest features of this house is a vide which allows to enjoy beautiful views of the Mont Blanc mountain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eric &amp; Flo, beauty at 1250 meter height</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/projects/20200402_eric_and_flo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/projects/20200402_eric_and_flo/</guid>
      <description>The Eric &amp;amp; Flo is one of our showroom models. We built this house in 2012 in The Lozère at a height of 1250 meters. In winter it gets seriously cold here, temperatures of -15 degrees Celcius are the norm. Last time we visited this client was in February 2019 en then they had half a meter of snow.
  The simplicity of the design is striking. A simple tilted roof and a wooden planks bardage on the outside with modern corners, and no stick-through miters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Josephine, minimalist to the max</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/projects/20200404_josephine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/projects/20200404_josephine/</guid>
      <description>The Josephine is a combination of panel and cross laminated timber, or CLT. The walls are traditional panel walls that you will see everywhere nowadays, while the overlay structure is made from CLT, 10 cm massive wood. The inside walls are finished with multiplex which creates an industrial interior.
  The glass facade is what it it all about. This house is located on the edge of a small village, overlooking farmland the the South-West.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Beautiful Design</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200326_goed_gelukt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200326_goed_gelukt/</guid>
      <description>We are builders and we are proud of our houses because of the techniques and materials that we use. Our houses are robust, sturdy, they have very high insulation values and the are build to withstand ages. But all that means nothing when it comes to aesthetics.
  A nice design is just that, nice, and that is why we often cooperate with the architects from OxL. Because no matter how nice our designs are, these OxL boys always manage to make it nicer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A beautiful design, the At &amp; Alet</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/projects/20200326_beautiful_design/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/projects/20200326_beautiful_design/</guid>
      <description>We are builders and we are proud of our houses because of the techniques and materials that we use. Our houses are robust, sturdy, they have very high insulation values and they are build to withstand ages. But all that means nothing when it comes to aesthetics.
A nice design is just that, nice, and that is why we often cooperate with the architects from OxL. Because no matter how nice our designs are, these OxL guys always manage to make it nicer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amber house, overlooking the hills from your terrace</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/projects/20200406_tombeboeuf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/projects/20200406_tombeboeuf/</guid>
      <description>This house we built in 2016 in Tombeboeuf, right between Bordeaux and Toulouse. Again a traditional loghouse with a larch facade, or &amp;ldquo;bardage en melèze&amp;rdquo; as they say in France. Massive beams supporting the roof.
  Our marketing manager Vaida on the terrace. She felt pity to leave the house as she liked both the house and the environment, but duty calls, we have to work on the next house&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>