<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Start on Lithouse</title>
    <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/start/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Start on Lithouse</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.lithouse.eu/start/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>We are Lithouse</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/start/01_we_are_lithouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/start/01_we_are_lithouse/</guid>
      <description>We are Lithouse. We build top quality wooden houses. Beautiful wooden houses, made to last for ages, made to measure, made for comfort.
  We specialise in solid, durable, energy-efficient houses. We try to use natural and ecological materials where we can. And we pride ourselves in making beautiful houses, not just run-of-the-mill standard living boxes but beautiful designs that make you feel happy every time you come home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Only top-quality</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/start/10_only_top_quality/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/start/10_only_top_quality/</guid>
      <description>We only build top-quality. No quick fixes, no rush jobs, only solutions that will last. We prefer simple reliable technologies and stable solutions. We take our time to design, and we take our time to produce and assemble. We prefer things that are stable and don&amp;rsquo;t break.
  We want to build for ourselves, and for the next generations. It is not difficult, it&amp;rsquo;s just a matter of caring more about build-quality than about market share, because we think that comes automatically if you keep your eye on quality and customer satisfaction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Craftmanship and Experience</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/start/20_craftmanship_and_experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/start/20_craftmanship_and_experience/</guid>
      <description>Craftmanship is difficult to measure. It is a combination of training and experience, and of interest and willingness to perform and to make things better.
  It is about pride about your own job, about understanding that what you do is special and that you are able to deliver quality. We surely feel like that about our products and about the ways we work.
  We have no company slogans, we are just carpenters with a drive to build something nice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We build made-to-measure</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/start/60_we_build_made_to_measure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/start/60_we_build_made_to_measure/</guid>
      <description>We build made-to-measure. No standard catalogue, only designs to your requirements. Takes a little extra effort, pays out for a lifetime.
  As far as cost is concerned there is not much difference because we have small factories and no big production lines that need to churn out massive numbers of houses. There is a little extra cost for the design stage, but it is minimal when compared to your total project cost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We build all over Europe</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/start/80_we_build_all_over_europe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/start/80_we_build_all_over_europe/</guid>
      <description>We can build everywhere in Europe, but mainly in France and The Netherlands. We produce in Lithuania, our installation teams travel to your building site.
  Depending on the size of your project we show up with tree to six men teams, and we will take somewhere between five and twelve weeks to fully build your house. A log house normally takes slightly more time, but only slightly.
  Our main markets at the moment are France and The Netherlands, but we also build in Portugal, Belgium and Denmark.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>