<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>log houses on Lithouse</title>
    <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/tags/log-houses/</link>
    <description>Recent content in log houses on Lithouse</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.lithouse.eu/tags/log-houses/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Yellow and blue log house</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20210215_yellow-and_blue_log_house/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20210215_yellow-and_blue_log_house/</guid>
      <description>With temperatures going down in Lithuania, and wind coming from the North-East, usually after a few days the Dutch go skating. And indeed, with Lithuanian temperatures going down to -25 Celcius, the ice started growing in The Netherlands and then the Dutch get into this frenzy where they all hope for the Great Event: the Elfstedentocht.
  And with Covid-19 the Dutch government did not want to let that happen, twenty thousand people on the ice was not a good idea, but also, they were reluctant to call off an event for which the Dutch had been waiting more than twenty years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New loghouse in Oosterwold</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20210122_loghuis_in_oosterwold/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20210122_loghuis_in_oosterwold/</guid>
      <description>Just handed over to client: a new loghouse in Oosterwold, Netherlands. Inspired by the Eric &amp;amp; Flo, 120 m2 brutto surface.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cold</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20210115_cold/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20210115_cold/</guid>
      <description>It is well known that timber from the North is heavier. It grows slower, and it is more dense. Better quality wood.
We came back from a business meeting just South of Vilnius and when we drove through a forest, we made this short movie. Nice, made us think of slow growing pine.
  And then in the evening when we came back from work, we looked at the dashboard and saw the temperature&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Larch getting grey</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20210112_larch_getting_grey/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20210112_larch_getting_grey/</guid>
      <description>We often use larch on the facades of our houses, because it is very weather resistant. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t rot, needs no maintenance, protects your house for fifty years.
But there is one thing about larch that is not to everybodies liking: it turns grey. Some people like the natural greying of larch, because it is natural. But others prefer to keep the original colours, for instance as in this house.
  We like the greying, but if you want to keep the original yellowish-orange tint of larch, then you must treat the facade with special products.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eric &amp; Flo</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20210111_eric_and_flo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20210111_eric_and_flo/</guid>
      <description>The Eric &amp;amp; Flo still is, after eight years, the house for which we receive most requests.
  These photos we received today from our clients in the Lozère. Winter wonderland with a beautiful house&amp;hellip;
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wooden logs and cracks</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20201229_wooden_logs_and_cracks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20201229_wooden_logs_and_cracks/</guid>
      <description>Log houses and cracks Log houses are built from wooden logs, that is: solid or laminated wooden beams, from eight centimeters thick upto thirty centimeters thick. We usually build our walls twelve or sixteen centimeters thick. Twelve is more than enough for a two-level house, but if you got money to spare then sixteen centimeters just looks nice. Otherwise there is little difference.
  But what about cracks? Yes, especially solid wooden logs do crack, and quite a bit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Russian wooden houses</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200409_old_russian_wooden_houses/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200409_old_russian_wooden_houses/</guid>
      <description>In East Europe wooden houses are everywhere. In the smaller villages almost every houses is a wooden house. Until recently these house were a little different from the house that we build:
 round logs, not laminated no additional insulation a little air leak here and there is ok lots of beautiful decorations painted.    And then finally: often without a serious foundation. Especially in Siberia houses are built with a minimal foundation on top of the permafrost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life expectancy of a wooden house</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200405_life_expectancy_of_a_log_house/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200405_life_expectancy_of_a_log_house/</guid>
      <description>Contrary to popular belief, wooden houses have a very high life expectancy. Of course wood should be protected from humidity, but if the owner takes care of his house it will last very long. When designing a wooden house we make sure that water can always escape from the house and that walls are ventilated. What would then be life expectancy of a wooden house?
We have several examples of old wooden houses in Europe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eric &amp; Flo, beauty at 1250 meter height</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/projects/20200402_eric_and_flo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/projects/20200402_eric_and_flo/</guid>
      <description>The Eric &amp;amp; Flo is one of our showroom models. We built this house in 2012 in The Lozère at a height of 1250 meters. In winter it gets seriously cold here, temperatures of -15 degrees Celcius are the norm. Last time we visited this client was in February 2019 en then they had half a meter of snow.
  The simplicity of the design is striking. A simple tilted roof and a wooden planks bardage on the outside with modern corners, and no stick-through miters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three types of walls</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200401_three_types_of_walls/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200401_three_types_of_walls/</guid>
      <description>Lithouse build houses with three types of walls:
 panel walls log walls cross laminated timber walls  They all have pro&amp;rsquo;s and con&amp;rsquo;s, let&amp;rsquo;s dive into the details.
Panel walls Panel walls are essentially hollow boxes filled with insulation material. You build a frame from 195 x 60 mm beams, and front and back you close with an 18 mm OSB-plate. Now you have a hollow box, say 2 x 3 meters and 231 mm thick.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Beautiful Design</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200326_goed_gelukt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200326_goed_gelukt/</guid>
      <description>We are builders and we are proud of our houses because of the techniques and materials that we use. Our houses are robust, sturdy, they have very high insulation values and the are build to withstand ages. But all that means nothing when it comes to aesthetics.
  A nice design is just that, nice, and that is why we often cooperate with the architects from OxL. Because no matter how nice our designs are, these OxL boys always manage to make it nicer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A beautiful design, the At &amp; Alet</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/projects/20200326_beautiful_design/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/projects/20200326_beautiful_design/</guid>
      <description>We are builders and we are proud of our houses because of the techniques and materials that we use. Our houses are robust, sturdy, they have very high insulation values and they are build to withstand ages. But all that means nothing when it comes to aesthetics.
A nice design is just that, nice, and that is why we often cooperate with the architects from OxL. Because no matter how nice our designs are, these OxL guys always manage to make it nicer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amber house, overlooking the hills from your terrace</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/projects/20200406_tombeboeuf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/projects/20200406_tombeboeuf/</guid>
      <description>This house we built in 2016 in Tombeboeuf, right between Bordeaux and Toulouse. Again a traditional loghouse with a larch facade, or &amp;ldquo;bardage en melèze&amp;rdquo; as they say in France. Massive beams supporting the roof.
  Our marketing manager Vaida on the terrace. She felt pity to leave the house as she liked both the house and the environment, but duty calls, we have to work on the next house&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Timelapse assembly of a loghuis</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200327_assembling_a_log_house/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/news/20200327_assembling_a_log_house/</guid>
      <description>In 2017 we built a loghouse on an island in The Netherlands. Quite an operation: getting a permit to drive a 24-ton truck onto the dike, then unloading to a barge, and then unloading on the island. After returning from a project in the Alps this was a little different for our assembly crew, going to work every day with tug boat.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Timelapse assembly of a loghuis</title>
      <link>https://www.lithouse.eu/timelapse/20200327_assembling_a_log_house/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lithouse.eu/timelapse/20200327_assembling_a_log_house/</guid>
      <description>In 2017 we built a loghouse on an island in The Netherlands. Quite an operation: getting a permit to drive a 24-ton truck onto the dike, then unloading to a barge, and then unloading on the island. After returning from a project in the Alps this was a little different for our assembly crew, going to work every day with tug boat.
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>